Inherently, if you're following some
kind of like playbook
that has worked in the past, it's highly
likely it's not going to work now
because the pace of change is so fast.
>> This is CMO Insider, where you'll get
candid takes from marketing power
players. My name's Lara O'Reilly. I'm a
senior correspondent at Business
Insider. And today, I'm here with
Charlie from Nothing. Now, Charlie
Smith, your chief brand officer at
Nothing, a tech brand you can pride
yourself on your minimalist kind of chic
design, headphones, smartphones,
wearables. And you joined, I think,
earlier this year?
>> Very recently, yeah. So, I joined at the
beginning of January after 7 years at
Loewe, the Spanish luxury fashion brand
owned by LVMH.
>> And what brought you to Nothing? What
was What was so compelling?
>> I knew after kind of that 7-year stint I
wanted to do something different. And
Nothing just really appealed to me as a
brand. First off, it's British, and I'm
deeply patriotic and love the idea of
being able to create another British
superbrand. I think the last one to
emerge here was probably Dyson.
So, that's very exciting. And then also,
I think the aesthetic and the values of
the company really appealed to me. And I
kind of um
kind of retrofuturism, you know, it
reminds me of kind of like '90s Casio
and Blade Runner and all of that kind of
fun stuff. And I think what what Carl's
been trying to do is to
>> Carl
>> Carl Pei, sorry. I should say Carl Carl
Pei, the founder of um Nothing,
previously of OnePlus, who, you know,
he's an incredible person to work with,
real visionary, and has built Nothing, I
think, very much in a community-driven
way. Like, we've got this incredibly
engaged community. It's It's very open
in the way that sort of Apple and Sam-
Samsung are probably actually kind of
very closed. And that kind of really
appealed to me. It felt very modern.
>> And And what's the brief then? Why did
they need to bring in a chief brand
officer, you, at this time?
>> Well, I think um
we really want to be the most
fashionable tech brand
there's been for a while, and it's a
pretty low bar. Um
cuz I think most tech tech is deeply
unfashionable, right? Again, I was I was
trying to think about it, and I was
really going back to like things like
the G-Shock watch as being something
that was like genuinely a trend and
genuinely cool. I think obviously Apple
did it a bit in the late '90s with, you
know, the iPod and stuff. That really
felt like a kind of like cool accessory.
In in marketing in general, not just in
tech, there was this trend
in roughly that that same period outside
of luxury fashion where
performance marketing was the new
exciting thing, and lots of brands began
chasing kind of like conversion and
efficiency, and kind of really focusing
on the data at the expense of brand
building.
And ultimately, I think we can see, if
you look at Nike's share price, what
that's done for them, that that pivot.
Whereas, me kind of growing up in in my
early career, they were
the bar in terms of kind of cultural
brand marketing, and that's why they
became so cool.
>> But on the flip side, is that because
there aren't things like mass reach
vehicles like TV aren't aren't aren't
what they were? You can't do that like
iconic 30-second spot in the same way.
>> 100%. And actually, the way that I
described it as at Loewe is that
we had to act like a publisher, like a
kind of magazine
in our own right. So,
you know, instead of doing three big
campaigns a year, we moved to doing like
two shoots a week.
It's a different model of working, but I
think you can have the same cultural
impact that you could before, but it's
more of like a drip feed thing.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's why nothing So, we just
announced Charli XCX as our first global
brand ambassador and share shareholder
in the brand. I I think it's a really
big moment for us as a company and I've
definitely seen that it's kind of the
pick up and traction from it has been,
you know, really strong.
>> That's such a get. This is someone at
the the kind of like the height of their
career. Um
also I imagine a brand ambassador that a
Coke or a Dove might might not feel
comfortable with. Why does Charli XCX
and the Nothing brand like work well
together?
>> I think one of the reasons why is that
it kind of that
it was a rallying against the fake
perfection of social media and that
world in a way. I think, you know, she's
previously described Brat as being like,
you know, sort of a strappy top, no bra,
pack of [__] and a Bic lighter. You
know, it's kind of this this rawness and
this realness
um that I think really resonated with
her community and this kind of younger
audience.
I think for for Nothing we're kind of
railing against the sort of boringness
that has taken over tech and hardware
recently. I remember going to hi-fi
shops growing up and it was super
exciting. There were all of these
hi-fi stacks with like flashing lights
and scrolling text. And you know, my
hi-fi used to say good morning to me
when I turned it on.
Um I feel like we've lost some of that
playfulness and personality. So it kind
of feels quite powerful to me to have
this kind of alignment of
you know, being a bit kind of
countercultural and sort of believing
that there's kind of an alternate
exciting future out there that's maybe
not the present that we've been living
in.
>> Mhm.
But I guess for all like the the kind of
the clinical aspects to what they do,
you know, these are hugely successful
companies that are very mass market all
over the world. They have huge marketing
budgets. So how do you kind of cut
through
a time when, you know, Apple's marketing
budget is in the multi-millions so and
Samsung's is in the billions.
>> I think when you're small, you can't
follow the same playbook as your bigger
competitors because it'll just be a drop
in the ocean. So, you you have to take
on guerrilla techniques. And I love this
example um
uh about Bumble, right? When when it
first launched is that they went into
loads of college campuses and put up
posters saying, "No Instagram, no
Facebook, no Bumble." And so, all of the
students were like, "Wait, what's
Bumble? Why am I allowed to use that?"
And it was super cheap to do cuz they
literally just printed out A4 sheets.
And then they also um
kind of paid student ambassadors to wear
Bumble merch and turn up late to
lectures that everyone turned around and
looked at them. You know, I think stuff
like that is
is actually really creative and
imaginative. And you know, we're
thinking of things that we can do. So,
for example, when we launched our pink
phone, the the 4A, we actually
graffitied our own billboards with uh
pink spray paint. Um and also our store,
you know, with things like I miss Paris
Hilton.
>> [laughter]
>> How do you kind of maintain that element
to your marketing as you get bigger?
You're looking to massively scale up in
the US. You're opening new stores.
Presumably, you you want to expand
globally. The idea is to be not just a
challenger, but hopefully to challenge
some of these these bigger tech giants.
So, how do you maintain what what feels
super creative, but but also perhaps
can't be mass-produced?
>> Uh I think if if we really want to
become the most loved uh tech company
for this generation,
we need to show how we're kind of giving
back to culture and actually
really sort of, you know,
leaving it with more than than than when
we first kind of got involved. And I
think some brands
are very obviously just like
sort of hijacking culture or kind of
taking from it. That's why I think it's
really important that take music as an
example. You know, I really want to in
the future be able to create like a
platform where we can support emerging
artists and kind of, you know, show them
to a a new audience.
>> And now a word from our sponsor,
LinkedIn Ads, to talk about how to cut
the bull spend from your marketing
budget.
>> Marketing leaders [music] today are
under more pressure than ever to prove
real impact and concrete business
outcomes. [music] I'm joined by Keith
Browning, Director of Global Brand
Marketing at LinkedIn, to learn [music]
more. What makes LinkedIn uniquely
suited to deliver measurable business
outcomes, especially in B2B?
>> LinkedIn is the largest professional
network in the world, so we're built for
this. We're built for B2B. So that means
firstly, being able to find the right
people. So, you know, you can target by
job title or seniority, company, etc.
But there's also the professional
context component as well. So people
come to LinkedIn to to learn, to
evaluate potential solutions, and
certainly to make buying decisions as
well.
>> What's your biggest challenge right now
as a marketer? As I say, you're you're
kind of advancing in in the US I mean, I
know you exist in the US, but you're
you're you're moving there in a big way.
>> So for for the US, I think
we we have quite a few plans, and I
think Charli XCX being one of them.
Obviously, she's a British artist, but
with, you know, huge cultural relevance
in the US, and we're also opening stores
um was kind of a a store/studio in San
Francisco, and also another store in New
York. I think one of one of the biggest
challenges
not just as a marketer, but for the
industry more broadly at the moment is
the cost of memory. Um cuz I I'm not
sure if you're aware, but it's it's
increasing exponentially. Um so that's
like an interesting challenge as we grow
to kind of navigate the next 18 months.
>> And does that become a brand challenge
for you? I mean, it sounds like a you
know, a manufacturing one, but
>> I think it's it's going to be a
challenge over the next 6 months. I
think you're going to see most tech
companies putting their prices up.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and that's going to be an interesting
thing to explain to consumers cuz for a
very long time we've been used to the
price of technology decreasing.
>> Mhm.
>> And it it feels counterintuitive as
we're on the cusp of this AI revolution
for the price to be going up, not down.
>> Mhm. And what is your your AI
positioning? We've been speaking mostly
about your kind of hardware products,
your your phones and and earbuds and so
on, but
um
you are um embracing AI in in your in
your OS.
>> I think our our long-term plan for AI,
you know, is is that
all devices are going to become AI
native in the next couple of years and
that we're going to move from this kind
of app world to a more agentic world
that's more kind of widget-based where
essentially, you know, the the interface
can adapt to your needs and deliver you
the relevant information that you
require. So, everything that we're
building now is kind of towards that
vision.
>> And how do you think AI kind of stands
at the moment sort of as a brand? It
feels like there's a bit of an anti-AI
backlash going on, especially among Gen
Z. We're seeing lots of, you know, boos
at commencement speeches and
>> For sure. And I I think, you know,
we're calling our sort of AI-powered
products essential because it's more
about what they do. It's like this is a
better version of dictation. I think a
lot of these
leaders in tech of these AI companies
are really talking up AGI and the fact
that AI is going to take over our jobs
in order to inflate [snorts] the the
valuation of the company and get more
funding.
But I I strongly believe that that's not
the reality that we're heading towards.
I think if you look at the industrial
revolution, there were sort of headlines
in the newspapers that machines were
going to take our jobs. And I I I really
believe that we're going to enter a new
era of creativity because like me for
example, I now if I think of an idea, I
can build it myself. To me, AI at the
moment that is incredible tool for
creativity and productivity and it's
really a kind of marketing and a
branding problem that's creating this
very strong backlash towards it. Cuz all
of these kids by the way who are anti-AI
are on ChatGPT the whole time.
>> So but you so you're a marketer then.
How do you how do you solve a problem
like the AI brand problem right now?
>> The focus has to be on the value it can
deliver, not on it as a as a sort of
concept with kind of like robotics and
kind of all of that stuff, you know.
>> Right.
>> I think it's interesting right if you
compare
the approach of the US and China. In In
China, AI is just being implemented in
in different categories and different
businesses in a very practical way and
no one's talking up this kind of sort
of, you know, artificial intelligence
kind of robotic future and so people are
much more comfortable with it.
>> How's it changed how how you work and
the people that you hire?
>> Yeah, going back to this point on kind
of creativity and productivity, we're
trying to automate everything that we
can so that these businesses usual tasks
of analytics and optimization and data
reporting can all basically be done no
longer manually but but kind of using AI
so that the very talented humans we have
on the team can spend less time on the
reporting and more time on coming up
with great ideas to move the business
forward. So yeah, I sometimes think that
maybe we've just reached this point of
kind of peak work and that actually
we're going to have more time in the
future to come up with ideas and be
creative.
>> And now a word from our sponsor LinkedIn
Ads to talk about how to cut the bull
spend from your marketing budget.
>> LinkedIn's Cut the Bull Spend campaign
urges marketers to rethink how they
evaluate performance [music] and where
their budgets actually drive impact. I'm
here with Keith Browning, director of
global [music] brand marketing at
LinkedIn, to learn more. How do you
define bull spend [music] in practical
terms?
>> So, I'd say bull spend is really wasted
advertising spend. [music] It's an
investment that leads to a great-looking
dashboard. So, the numbers look good,
the arrows are going in the right
direction, but really it's not actually
doing anything to to drive the business
forward, so it doesn't hold up to
scrutiny.
>> How does LinkedIn help marketers reduce
waste and increase efficiency in real
terms? [music]
>> At LinkedIn, you don't have to pay for
attention from people who, you know, are
never going to buy from you. A mass
reach works great if you're selling
breakfast cereal, not so much if you're
selling, you know, CRMs. That's really
where LinkedIn is different.
>> There does seem to be a big trend in
tech at the moment and um in Silicon
Valley more more kind of broadly about
going direct, right? Like bypassing
traditional media, traditional reviews
maybe if, you know, starting your own
podcast, starting your own media brand.
Is that something that you sort of
subscribe to as well?
>> I don't really see it so much as
bypassing as more just kind of working
across all of the different sort of
available channels that there are. One
of the things that, you know, this is
even before my time at Nothing, the the
team had done this amazing job of acting
kind of like a new age kind of content
creator and publisher. Now, other brands
are approaching us to work with us as a
content creator, which is a really
>> How does that work?
>> Well, because I think they see us as
experts in being able to create this
kind of new age media, you know, for
YouTube, for social. And so, we can do
these kind of brand collaborations where
we're telling telling different stories.
Cuz that's the thing, I think
we're not just telling product stories
on social media, right? We're we're
telling stories across tech and across
culture. And that's really what when I
say I want us to act like a publisher, I
want it to be like a new age media
version of reading like Wired magazine
or something where it's like you have
your tech section, you have your fashion
section, you have your music section.
And I think that's why or like how you
can build a community around the brand
cuz people know you're not just
selling products. You're you're also
participating in culture and you're as
interested as they are in the different
trends that are emerging and how that
all kind of connects together.
And I think we want to give people that
access. We want to let people in and
make them feel part of the company.
>> It like it's a mix between luxury and
startup, the kind of thing that you're
you're doing. Like there's there's like
the the the grassroots level and then
the going up to the you know, the
incredible like billboards that you have
in Shoreditch at the moment with with
Charli XCX. I'm I'm wondering um
how other marketers at bigger brands
should think about applying some of
these playbooks.
>> Inherently, if you're following some
kind of like playbook
that has worked in the past, it's highly
likely it's not going to work now
because the pace of change is so fast.
To me, that would be like my number one
piece of advice to marketers out there,
which is like
be incredibly hungry to learn
about your customer and where they're
spending their time and how they're
doing it.
And then think about how you can then
show up in an authentic way in that
place
in a way that's going to really matter
to them.
>> Mhm.
What are some of the newer platforms
that you're getting excited about? Or
maybe they don't even have to be new,
but but kind of new to the brand.
>> I I'm I'm really fascinated um
I I think it's less of a kind of new
type of platform, but I'm really
fascinated at the moment by
kind of this whole thing of like
clipping networks. Those clips people
are watching on YouTube, they're
watching them on TikTok, they're
watching them on you know, Instagram
reels. So, that's definitely something
that I'm finding fascinating. I'm also
fascinated by the fact that I've met a
few people now who
have created accounts solely using AI.
And if you follow the logical
progression of that thought, right? If
more and more people do that and more
and more social media just becomes
AI content, will we as humans want to
spend less and less time on it?
And therefore will, you know, Meta and
Google and others then try and fight it
and block it off the platforms cuz they
know that actually we as humans want to
see content from other humans. So,
that's I'm just constantly thinking
about like what's the dynamic and how
will trends change? And I think one of
the reactions to this might be
that brands start doing more in-person
physical events and activations again.
Which also is kind of interesting.
>> That seems to be the the thing that gets
cut through now, right? Is people It's
not whatever the the act of, you know,
the the post was on Nike's accounts. It
was the 10 people taking pictures of it
or or taking videos of it on TikTok and
one of those went viral and that's how
it how it reached reached a bigger
audience.
>> Exactly. Like the Arsenal players at
5:00 in the morning outside the Emirates
Stadium.
>> Glad you mentioned that.
>> Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I yeah, I I think
that's why it's incredibly hard to
predict virality, but I think it's
really is really important when you're
coming up with ideas to try and think
like
what's something about this that people
might want to share with each other and
then how can we help kind of like build
on that idea and amplify it.
>> And just to end on Shelley, um really
interested I I imagine there's a lot of
people who'd be interested in working
with you or a brand like Nothing. What
could people do to stand out to make
sure that that they'll capture your
attention? Be it
on social media or on a on a resume in
an interview. like what are the kind of
things that stick out to you?
>> Well, I think first off,
you know, you'd be surprised. I've I've
hired people from their LinkedIn
messages before.
>> So, you're going to get a deluge now.
>> [laughter]
>> I I I do think that being proactive and
reaching out to people is important. Um
I've I've had someone write an album as
their resume and put it on vinyl and
send the vinyl.
And that like
>> hire them?
>> We we we we first off we we play we
played it in the office. We all loved
it. Uh then basically invited them for
an interview. We didn't actually have a
job opening at the time, but it got an
interview, which I think just shows that
you know, it it's really powerful to to
do things like that because it's it's
showing your, you know, entrepreneurial
spirit, your creativity, you know, all
of those things together.
>> That set the bar quite [laughter] high.
Okay.
>> Yeah. Now everyone's just going to be
their CVs into albums.
>> Well, you know, at least it's physical
copy. It's human endeavor. That's that's
what we want to hear in this world of
AI. Charlie, thank you so much for
joining us on CMO Insider.
>> Thank you. I really enjoyed it.
>> And if you enjoyed this interview,
please like and subscribe for more CMO
Insider content. You can also find more
marketing news, analysis, scoops,
interviews at businessinsider.com.